Darius Elphick

Contact

Phone: +447792526693

Information

E-mail: hi@tenaciousdarius.dev

LinkedIn: http://www.linkedin.com/in/dariuselphick

Personal Profile Senior Frontend and Mobile Developer with over ten years of experience building, testing and maintaining large-scale commercial applications in the media and transport industries. Experience building fully tested software across the stack as well as managing agile development teams practicing TDD and BDD.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Web Development and Testing:

- HTML5, CSS3 and Responsive Web Design
- OO Javascript, ReactJS, Redux and JQuery
- Node.js and Express
- Jest, Mocha, Chai, PhantomJS, Karma, Storybook, Cucumber and WebDriver.io
- Webpack, Grunt
- Browser Support including IE 8 11, Edge, Chrome, Firefox and Safari
- Accessibility Standards including Semantic HTML and ARIA Tags
- Design Patterns for building and testing large, scalable web applications including MVVM, MVC and React Redux

Behaviour and Test Driven Development: Experience leading and mentoring teams practicing TDD and BDD.

Web Services: Designing, integrating with and testing REST and SOAP web services using SOAPUI.

DevOps: AWS (EC2, S3, RDS, Route 53, CloudWatch, IAM, Lamda), Docker, Network Management and Security.

Version Control: Git and Mercurial

Methodologies: Experience working in Agile teams using SCRUM, SAFE, FDD and XP. Certified SCRUM Master.

Professional Experience The Trainline, London.

Engineering Team Lead

Apr. 2019 to Oct. 2019

- Managed a team of seven Frontend Developers working on the company's mobile web product, including day to day management of timelines and prioritisation, mentorship, setting objectives and performance review.
- Introduced new testing and release process to improve quality, working closely with other leads and the QA team. Included specifying and implementing an acceptance testing schema using an in-house built framework harnessing Webdriver.io.

BBC Global News, London.

Senior Front End Developer

Apr. 2017 to Mar. 2019

- Developed and maintained the BBC Features Websites as well as other commercial projects.
- Managed a team of two other Front End Developers practicing TDD to build a new PWA version of the sites using React and Redux and tested with Jest and Storybook.

BBC Studios, London.

Senior Front End Developer

Aug. 2015 to Mar. 2017

• Worked with several teams throughout the BBC on development, testing and release of the BAFTA-nominated Sir David Attenborough's Story of Life, a cross-platform app for accessing archived nature documentaries.

Web Developer

Aug. 2014 to Aug. 2015

• Migrated all BBC Features sites to a new platform built in house using Node.js and Express. Contributed to the design of the new framework, called Glaze.

SyQic Limited, Gerrards Cross and Kuala Lumpur.

Technical and Development Specialist

Jul. 2012 to Aug. 2014

• Built the universal, localised iOS app for Yoonic, the company's primary IPTV product. Designed robust app structure via the MVC-N design pattern.

Aberystwyth University, Aberystwyth.

Computer Science Advisor

Sept. 2011 to May 2012

Cyngor Gwynedd Council, Caernarfon.

Programmer/Analyst on Work Experience

July 2011 to Sept. 2011

Programmer/Analyst on Work Experience

June 2009 to Sept. 2010

EDUCATION

Aberystwyth University, Aberystwyth.

Sept. 2007 to June 2012

MEng (1st Class Hons) Software Engineering

Additional Information Other Skills: Fluent Welsh speaker.

Other Achievements: Have fundraised over £3,400 for the Mental Health Foundation over the last three years in bake sales and sponsorship to run both the Hackney Half Marathon and the London Marathon.

Interests: Some of my interests include video games, reading and travel. Within the past year, the best game I've played is Civilization VI, the best books I've read are Born to Run by Christopher McDougall and Salt Fat Acid Heat by Samin Nosrat, and the best destination I've visited was Milford Sound, New Zealand. I'm also a keen baker.

Referees

References available on request.